hhl.de 2016-12-01

# Privacy | HHL Europe, Germany

## Privacy Statement

###  1\. Scope 

Protecting your personal data and therefore your privacy is a top priority for our enterprise. With this privacy statement, we would like to inform you which data HHL Leipzig Graduate School of Management (HHL gemeinnützige GmbH) collects and processes when you visit and use its website. We observe legal requirements; specifically those arising from the German Data Protection Act (BDSG) and the German Broadcast Media Act (TMG).

###   
2\. What is personal data?

Personal data means any information concerning the personal or material circumstances of an identified or identifiable individual (section 3, paragraph 1 of BDSG). This includes, among other things, the address, name, e-mail address and telephone number. Details such as your marital status, insurance number or which websites you visited are considered personal data. We only collect, use and forward personal data if doing so is permitted by the German Data Protection Act or required by other law or you agreed to the collection of your data.

###  3\. What data is collected and processed?

####   
Access data/server log files

Any time you visit our website or use our services, data is automatically collected and stored in so-called server log files.   
These access data include but are not limited to:

  * name of the visited website
  * date and time of visit
  * data volume transmitted
  * notification of successful data retrieval
  * browser type, including version
  * user's operating system 
  * websites you previously visited
  * IP address
  * requesting provider

This log data is used for statistical evaluation, maintenance, safety and optimization of the services. If there is specific evidence of an illegal use, the provider reserves the right to review the data retroactively.

####  Contact

If you contact us via the contact form or e-mail, your data will be stored in order to process the inquiry and any subsequent questions. Please note that this information is transmitted unencrypted.

####  Salesforce

We use cloud-based services to process personal data during the admission and study process. Agreements in accordance with section 11 of BDSG have been concluded with the providers of these services (Salesforce) regulating the processing of the contract data and also allowing for processing outside the scope of the EU Data Protection Directive. Due to state authorities outside the EU being able to access to your data, we recommend that you do not upload particularly sensitive data (in accordance with section 3, paragraph 9 of BDSG) to the system but instead send them to your contact person via e-mail.  
By confirming you have read and accepted our Terms and Conditions and the Privacy Statement, your consent to the processing of personal data as described above will be logged. The consent may only be revoked with effect for the future. At this stage, we can only assure logical deletion of the data stored so far. Revoking your consent will be accompanied by further limitations during the application and study process about which we will gladly inform you on a case-by-case basis. Salesforce participates in the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. For more details visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000KzLyAAK>.

####  Blog comments and contributions

Any details such as your name, e-mail address, homepage and content submitted as part of a blog comment or contribution will solely be used for the purposes of blog commenting. If you compose blog comments or other contributions, we will store your IP address for our own security. This step is based on the fact that we can be held liable for illegal comments and contributions (e.g., insults, forbidden political propaganda). 

#### Integration of third-party services and content

At times, we also integrate third-party content into our online offer. This includes, among other things, graphics from other websites or Google Maps. These third-party providers will be notified of your IP address; otherwise the content could not be displayed. We do not have any influence on whether the third-party providers store your e-mail address (e.g., for statistical purposes) but we seek to only use images where no such data is stored. As soon as we learn about IP addresses being stored, we will inform the user of this circumstance.

####  Registration feature

If you wish to use our offer, we will need the data which you submitted during the registration process. The data entered into the input during registration is collected.

####  Cookies 

To be able to offer you certain features on our website, we use cookies. These are small text files which allow for specific device-related information to be stored on your access device (PC, smartphone, etc.). Cookies serve the purpose of increasing the user-friendliness of our website (e.g., saving login data) as well as collecting statistical data about the website use to improve our offer following an analysis of the data. You can limit or prevent cookies from being stored to your computer by changing your browser settings. Please note, however, that you might no longer be able to use all the features on our website to their full extent when doing so.

####  Newsletter/MailChimp

You can subscribe to our newsletter informing you about HHL Leipzig and its latest offers.  
To send you the newsletter, we require a valid e-mail address from you. If you sign up for our newsletter, we will store your IP address and the date as proof in the event that a third person has misused the authorized recipient's e-mail address and signed up for the newsletter without the recipient's knowledge.  
We use MailChimp as a list provider to send out our newsletter. MailChimp is a service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC, 512 Means Street, Suite 404, Atlanta, GA 30318. Arrangements with the agent on data processing in accordance with section 11 of BDSG are in place. For further information on data protection at MailChimp, please visit <http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>.  
In addition to the fields of interest selected by you, you will also receive program-specific information from us on an irregular and event-related basis. You may revoke your consent to receiving this information at any time.

####  Google AdWords

This website uses Google AdWords and, in doing so, its conversion tracking feature as well. If you come to our website by clicking on a Google ad, Google AdWords will add cookies to your computer. These cookies become invalid after 30 days and do not serve as a means of personal identification. If you visit specific pages of the AdWords customer's website and the cookie has not yet expired, both Google and we, the customer, can see that the user clicked on the advertisement and was redirected to the current page. Every AdWords customer receives a different cookie. Cookies can therefore not be tracked over AdWords customer websites. The information collected with the help of the conversion cookies are used in the creation of conversion statistics for AdWords customers who have opted for conversion tracking. AdWords customers receive information about the total number of users which have clicked on their advertisement(s) and also how many of these customers were redirected to a website with a conversion tracking tag. However, these AdWords customers do not receive any information which would personally identify the users. If you do not wish to participate in the tracking process, you can block the Google AdWords conversion tracking cookie by changing your browser settings (block cookies from the www.googleadservices.com domain). Google's privacy statement on conversion tracking is available at [www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy](http://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy "Opens external link in new window").

####  WordPress.com

HHL's blog is based on the WordPress.com service. For the purposes of the statistical evaluation of user access, the website uses a tool by Automattic Inc., 60 29th Street, 343, San Francisco, CA 94110-4929, USA, which includes the use of tracking technology by Quantcast Inc., 201 3rd St, Floor 2, San Francisco, CA 94103-3153, USA and com Score Inc., 11950 Democracy Drive, Suite 600 Reston, VA 20190, USA. WordPress.com also uses cookies, which are text files placed on your computer, to enable an analysis of the use of the website. This includes information on your pattern of use and is stored on servers based in the United States. Your IP address will be anonymized before it is saved. You can prevent the installation of cookies on your computer by changing your browser settings. Please note, however, that you might no longer be able to use all the features of this website to their full extent when doing so. You can opt out of the collection and use of data by Quantcast with future effect by clicking the "Click here to opt out" link, which will place an opt-out cookie in your browser: [www.quantcast.com/company/opt-out](https://www.quantcast.com/company/opt-out). If you delete all cookies on your computer, you will have to re-install the opt-out cookie. For further data protection information, please visit <http://automattic.com/privacy/>.

#### Google Analytics

Our website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Google provides a browser plug-in to deactivate Google Analytics at [tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de). Google Analytics uses cookies. These are small text files which enable the storage of user-related information on the user's end device. This allows for an analysis of the use of our website by Google. The information generated by the cookie about the use of our website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Please note that, on this website, Google Analytics was expanded by the "gat._anonymizeIp();" code to ensure IP masking. In the event that IP anonymization is activated, IP addresses will be shortened beforehand by Google within member states of the European Union or in other signatory states of the Treaty on the European Economic Area; therefore, your identity cannot be tracked. The full IP address will be transmitted to a Google Server in the USA and shortened there only on an exceptional basis. Arrangements with the agent on data processing in accordance with section 11 of BDSG are in place. To find out more, please visit <http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/privacyoverview.html>.

####  Google +1

Our website uses social media features from Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. When you access our website with Google plug-ins, a connection between your browser and the Google servers is established. Data is already transmitted to Google as part of this process. If you have a Google account, this data may be linked to it. If you do not wish to link this data to your Google account, please log out of Google before visiting our website. Interaction, particularly the use of the comment section or clicking a "+1" or "Share" button, will also be transmitted to Google. To find out more, please visit <http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy>.

####  Facebook

Our website uses features by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. When you access our website with Facebook plug-ins, a connection between your browser and the Facebook servers is established. Data is already transmitted to Facebook as part of this process. If you have a Facebook account, this data may be linked to it. If you do not wish to link this data to your Facebook account, please log out of Facebook before visiting our website. Interaction, particularly the use of the comment section or clicking a "Like" or "Share" button, will also be transmitted to Facebook. To find out more, please visit <https://de-de.facebook.com/about/privacy>.  
You can block the Facebook social plug-ins by using add-ons for your browser (e.g., Facebook Blocker).

####  Twitter

Our website uses features from Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. When you access our website with Twitter plug-ins, a connection between your browser and the Twitter servers is established. Data is already transmitted to Twitter as part of this process. If you have a Twitter account, this data may be linked to it. If you do not wish to link this data to your Twitter account, please log out of Twitter before visiting our website. Interaction, particularly clicking a "Retweet" button, will also be transmitted to Twitter. To find out more, please visit <https://twitter.com/privacy>.

####  YouTube

On our website, we embedded some features from YouTube, LLC 901 Cherry Ave. San Bruno, CA 94066 USA. For further information, please check the YouTube privacy policy.

####  Xing

Our website uses the "Share" button by Xing, Gänsemarkt 43, 20354 Hamburg, Germany. When you access our website, the browser establishes a direct connection with the Xing servers. We are not aware which data is transmitted to Xing as part of this direct connection and how it is used. According to Xing, no personal data is collected without clicking on the button.   
The latest privacy policy on the Xing "Share" button and additional information is available at <https://www.xing.com/app/share?op=data_protection>.

####  LinkedIn

On our website, we use plug-ins of the social network LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, California 94043, USA.  
Through the embedded plug-in, LinkedIn receives information that you accessed our website from your IP address. If you are logged into LinkedIn at the time, your visit to our website might be linked to your LinkedIn account. If you wish to prevent this, you should log out of LinkedIn before visiting our website or opt out of the collection of impression data from plug-ins by LinkedIn at <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=hb_ft_priv>, item 1.7.  
To find out more, please view LinkedIn's privacy policy: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=hb_ft_priv>.

#### Tumblr

On our website, we use the "Follow" button of the social network Tumblr, Tumblr Inc., 35 East 21st St, 10th Floor, New York, NY 10010, USA. Through the embedded "Follow" button, Tumblr receives information that you accessed our website from your IP address. If you are logged into Tumblr at the time, your visit to our website might be linked to your Tumblr account. If you wish to prevent this, you should log out of Tumblr before visiting our website. For further information on Tumblr's privacy policy, please visit <http://www.tumblr.com/policy/en/privacy>.

###  4\. Know your rights!

You have to right to obtain information free of charge on if and what personal data from we have stored. You also have the legal right to have incorrect personal data corrected, blocked and deleted if there is no legal obligation for us to retain it.  
To exercise your rights, please contact the Data Protection Officer of HHL Leipzig Graduate School of Management.

###  5\. Amendment of the Privacy Statement

With regard to the constant technical progress of the Internet and the development of laws and legislation, we reserve the right to adjust this Privacy Statement to technical and legal requirements at any time. 

Data Protection Officer  
HHL Leipzig Graduate School of Management   
Jahnallee 59  
04109 Leipzig  
datenschutz@hhl.de
